A Finding Aid to the American Federation of Arts Records, 1895-1993 (bulk 1909-1969), in the Archives of American Art AAA.amerfeda
Archives of American Art
- Annual Conventions, 1912-1963; Series 4; (boxes 14-16)
  - 50th Anniversary Convention, 1959 (Box 16)
    - Proceedings (Box 16)
    - Architects (Box 16)
    - Exhibitions (Box 16)
    - Honorary Committee (Box 16)
    - Photographs (Box 16)
    - Private Dinners (Box 16)
    - Press Releases (Box 16)
    - Clippings (Box 16)
    - Speakers Biographical Materials (Box 16)
    - Speakers Program (Box 16)
  - Convention, [1961] (Box 16)
    - Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 16)
    - Exhibitions (Box 16)
    - Clippings (Box 16)
    - Publicity (Box 16)
    - Arrangements (Box 16)
    - Speakers (Box 16)
    - Correspondence (Box 16)
    - Program (Box 16)
    - Speeches (Box 16)
    - Thank You Letters (Box 16)
  - Convention [ Dallas/Fort Worth, Texas], 1963 (Box 16)
    - Committee, 1962-1963 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence (Box 16)
    - Exhibitions (Box 16)
    - Planning (Box 16)
    - Publicity, 1962-1963 (Box 16)
    - Registration (Box 16)
    - Speakers (Box 16)
    - Thank You Letters (Box 16)
  - Convention [ Lincoln, Nebraska.; canceled], 1963 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 16)
- Exhibition Files, 1934-1969; Series 5; (boxes 17-78)
  This series is organized into 20 subseries:
  5.1: Exhibitions, General, 1942-1962
  5.2: Circulating Exhibitions, 1934-1959
  5.3: Annual Exhibitions, 1951-1969 (AFA nos. 51-1 through 69-20)
  5.4: Documentation Files for Annual Exhibitions, 1965-1967 (AFA nos.65-1 through 67-29)
  5.5: Report Forms for Exhibitions, 1948-1953
  5.6: Miscellaneous Exhibitions, 1951-1968
  5.7: State Department Exhibitions, 1949-1952
  5.8: Metropolitan Museum of Art Exhibitions, 1950-1956
  5.9: Contemporary Berlin Artists, 1950-1956 (AFA no. 48)
  5.10: Contemporary Color Lithography, 1951-1954 (AFA no. 96)
  5.11: Imaginary Portraits, 1951 (AFA no. 99)
  5.12: Metropolitan Museum of Art, Minishows, 1951-1956
  5.13: Life Exhibitions, 1951-1959
  5.14: Virginia Museum of Fine Arts Exhibitions, 1952-1956
  5.15: Addison Gallery Exhibitions, 1953-1955
  5.16: Canceled Exhibitions, 1953-1964
  5.17: New York State Council on the Arts Exhibitions, 1961-1964
  5.18: Rejected Exhibitions, 1961-1968
  5.19: Suggested Exhibitions, 1964-1967
  5.20: Photographs of Miscellaneous Exhibition Installations, undated
  - Exhibitions, General, 1942-1962; 5.1
    - Exhibitions, General, 1942-1947 (Box 17)
    - Eloise Spaeth's Files, 1947-1948 (Box 17)
    - Mrs. John Pope's Files, 1948 (Box 17)
    - Eloise Spaeth's Files, 1949 (Box 17)
    - Mrs. John Pope's Files, 1949 (Box 17)
    - Annual Report, 1949-1950 (Box 17)
    - Eloise Spaeth's Files, 1950 (Box 17)
    - Mrs. John Pope's Files, 1950 (Box 17)
    - Eloise Spaeth's Files, 1951 (Box 17)
    - Mrs. John Pope's Files, 1951 (Box 17)
    - Exhibitions, General, 1951-1962 (Box 17)
  - Circulating Exhibitions, 1934-1959; 5.2
    - Kentucky, Miscellaneous, 1955 (Box 17)
    - Louisiana, Tulane University, 1948 (Box 17)
    - Massachusetts (Box 17)
      - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1953 (Box 17)
      - The Smith College Museum of Art, 1953 (Box 17)
    - New York (Box 17)
      - Albany, New York State College for Teachers, 1948-1951 (Box 17)
      - New York State College of Ceramics, Alfred University, 1944-1948 (Box 17)
      - Cayuga Museum of History and Art, 1946-1947 (Box 17)
    - Buffalo (Box 17)
      - Buffalo Art Institute, 1945 (Box 17)
      - Grosvenor Library, 1945-1950 (Box 17)
    - Cortland, Cortland Free Library, 1944-1946 (Box 17)
    - Fredonia, State Teachers College, 1948-1956 (Box 17)
    - Geneseo, State University of New York Teachers College, 1955-1956 (Box 17)
    - New York (Box 17)
      - A.C.A. Gallery, undated (Box 17)
      - A-D Gallery, 1948-1951 (Box 17)
      - American British Art Center, 1944-1949 (Box 17)
      - American-Scandinavian Foundation, 1943-1946 (Box 17)
    - Art Directors Club, 1949-1955 (Box 17)
      - Buchholz Gallery, 1939-1950 (Box 17)
      - Columbia University, 1948-1950 (Box 17)
      - Council for Inter-American Cooperation, Inc., 1947-1951 (Box 17)
      - Easthampton, Long Island (Guild Hall), 1951-1955 (Box 17)
      - The East and West Association, 1942 (Box 17)
      - English Speaking Union, 1943-1945 (Box 17)
      - French Embassy, 1948 (Box 17)
      - Handy & Harman, 1948-1951 (Box 17)
      - Harmon Foundation, 1941-1950 (Box 17)
      - Hays Storage and Packing Company, 1945-1950 (Box 17)
      - Kennedy Gallery, 1943-1957 (Box 17)
      - Life Exhibitions, 1945-1955 (Box 17)
      - M. Grumbacher, 1939-1945 (Box 17)
      - M. Knoedler and Company, 1934-1949 (Box 18)
      - Midtown Galleries, 1943-1948 (Box 18)
      - Milch Gallery, 1939-1947 (Box 18)
      - Milton Snedecker Corporation, 1934-1952 (Box 18)
      - National Serigraph Society, 1945-1959 (Box 18)
      - New Age Gallery, Inc., 1950-1951 (Box 18)
      - Russell Sage Foundation, 1936-1941 (Box 18)
      - Society of Illustrators, 1938-1943 (Box 18)
    - Rochester Public Library, 1947-1951 (Box 18)
    - The University of Rochester Library, 1949-1958 (Box 18)
    - Troy, Russell Sage College, 1948 (Box 18)
    - Utica, Utica Public Library, 1945-1951 (Box 18)
    - Wellsville, Carnival Caravan, 1948-1950 (Box 18)
  - Annual Exhibitions (AFA nos. 51-1 through 69-20), 1951-1969; 5.3
    - 51-1: Paintings and Prints from the Upper Midwest, Photographs, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 51-2: Home and the Machine, Photographs, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 51-3: Eleven Dutch Printmakers, Photographs, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 51-4: A University Collects, Photographs, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 51-5: Mural for First National Bank in Tulsa, Photographs, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 51-6: Boris Margo: The Months, Photographs, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 51-7: House in Mexico by Anshen & Allen, San Francisco, Photographs, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 51-8: 1950 A.I.D. (American Institute of Design) Awards, Photographs, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 51-9: Art of the Photogram, Photographs, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 51-13: Louisiana Heritage by James Henri Ricau, Photographs, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 51-14: Six American Painters, Photographs, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 51-15: California Crafts, Photographs, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 51-16: Indian Watercolor Drawings of the Kalighat School, Photographs, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 51-17: Replicas of Ancient Egyptian Sculpture, Photographs and Negatives, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 51-18: Contemporary Italian Paintings, Photographs, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 51-21: Young Painters U.S.A., Photographs, 1951 (Box 18)
    - 52-1: 60th Annual American Exhibition from the Art Institute of Chicago, Photographs, 1952 (Box 18)
    - 52-3: Photographs by Brett Weston, Photographs, 1952 (Box 18)
    - 52-4: Sculpture: In Time and Place, Photographs, 1952 (Box 18)
    - 52-5: The Danish Poster, 1952 (Box 18)
    - 52-7: 1951 Annual A.I.D. Awards, Photographs, 1952 (Box 18)
    - 52-8: Thirty U.S. Contemporaries, Photographs, 1952 (Box 18)
    - 52-11: State and Territories, Photographs, 1952 (Box 18)
    - 52-17: Paintings by Vienna School Children, 1952-1954 (Box 18)
    - 52-23: Finnish Arts and Crafts, 1952-1954 (Box 18)
    - 53-1: Philadelphia International Watercolor Annual, 1952-1954 (Box 18)
    - 53-2: Graphic Art and Techniques, 1952-1954 (Box 18)
    - 53-3: Drawings by Leonardo DaVinci, 1953 (Box 18)
    - 53-4: British Children's Art, 1952-1954 (Box 18)
    - 53-5: American Watercolors, Drawings and Prints, 1952-1954 (Box 18)
    - 53-6: John Marin Etchings, 1952-1955 (Box 18)
    - 53-7: Daumier Lithographs, 1952-1954 (Box 19)
    - 53-8: National Academy Contemporaries, 1952-1954 (Box 19)
    - 53-9: Three Semi-Abstractionists, 1952-1954 (Box 19)
    - 53-10: Fifty Books of the Year, 1952-1955 (Box 19)
    - 53-11: Postwar German Color Prints, Photographs, 1953 (Box 19)
    - 53-12: Corcoran Twenty-third Biennial, 1952-1954 (Box 19)
    - 53-13: Modern Aubusson Tapestries, Report Forms, 1953 (Box 19)
    - 53-14: Five Contemporary Americans, 1952-1953 (Box 19)
    - 53-15: Postwar German Theater Design, 1952-1954 (Box 19)
    - 53-16: Seventh Brooklyn Museum Print Annual, 1952-1957 (Box 19)
    - 53-17: 1952 Annual A.I.D. Awards, 1952-1953 (Box 19)
    - 53-18: Biblical Paintings by Ben-Zion, 1953-1954 (Box 19)
    - 53-19: The Face of Humor, 1951-1954 (Box 19)
    - 53-20: Sculpture 1953, 1953-1954 (Box 19)
    - 53-21: Contemporary Swiss Architecture, 1951-1955 (Box 19)
    - 53-22: Room Portraits by David Payne, 1951-1954 (Box 19)
    - 53-23: Recent Architecture in Western Germany, 1953-1954 (Box 19)
    - 53-24: First International Carpet Design Competition, 1951-1954 (Box 19)
    - 53-25: New Work in Stained Glass, 1952-1953 (Box 19)
    - 53-25: New Work in Stained Glass, 1952-1953 (continued) (Box 20)
    - 53-26: Approaches to Drawing and Prints, 1953-1954 (Box 20)
    - 53-31: New Design Developments, 1953 (Box 20)
    - 53-32: Bridges Are Beautiful, 1953 (Box 20)
    - 53-36: Designs for Fountains, 1953 (Box 20)
    - 54-3: Design in Scandinavia, 1954-1957 (Box 20)
    - 54-3: Design in Scandinavia, 1954-1957 (continued) (Box 21)
    - 54-4: Designer Craftsmen U.S.A., 1954-1955 (Box 21)
    - 54-8: Art Schools USA, 1953-1954 (Box 21)
    - 54-9: The Child Craftsman, 1953-1955 (Box 21)
    - 54-10: A University Collects: University of Nebraska, 1953-1955 (Box 21)
    - 54-11: Watercolors and Drawings by Dutch and Flemish Artists, 1953-1955 (Box 21)
    - 54-12: The Opening of the West, 1954-1955 (Box 21)
    - 54-13: Medieval Architecture, 1953-1955 (Box 21)
    - 54-14: Silver and Stone, 1953-1956 (Box 21)
    - 54-15: The City and Its People, 1953 (Box 21)
    - 54-16: Religion and the Printmaker's Theme, 1953-1955 (Box 21)
    - 54-17: Side Door to Commerce, 1953-1955 (Box 21)
    - 54-18: Contemporary Color Lithography, 1954-1955 (Box 21)
    - 54-19: American Painting 1954, Photographs (Box 21)
    - 54-25: Highlights of American Painting, 1953-1956 (Box 21)
    - 54-27: AFA Trustees Collectors, 1953-1954 (Box 21)
    - 54-28: Smith College Collects, 1956 (Box 21)
    - 54-31: Sketches for Sculpture, 1954 (Box 21)
    - 54-41: Planned for Craftsmen, 1954-1955 (Box 21)
    - 54-42: Art Schools USA, 1954 (Box 21)
    - 54-43: Creative Jewelry, 1955-1956 (Box 22)
    - 55-1: Museum Purchase Fund, 1955 (Box 22)
    - 55-2: Corcoran Biennial, 1954-1956 (Box 22)
    - 55-3: Trends in Contemporary American Painting, 1954-1956 (Box 22)
    - 55-4: The First Century of Color Lithography, 1954-1956 (Box 22)
    - 55-5: Painter's Panorama, 1953-1956 (Box 22)
    - 55-6: New Talent in the USA, 1954-1956 (Box 22)
    - 55-7: Major Works in Minor Scale: Paintings and Sculpture by Major Italian Artists, 1954-1957 (Box 22)
    - 55-8: Accent Rugs, 1954-1956 (Box 22)
    - 55-9: A Collector's Choice, 1955 (Box 22)
    - 55-10: Nuremberg and the German World, 1954-1955 (Box 22)
    - 55-11: Art, Nature and the Fabric, 1954-1956 (Box 22)
    - 55-12: Sculpture in Silver from Islands in Time, 1953-1955 (Box 22)
    - 55-13: World at Work, 1954-1956 (Box 23)
    - 55-14: Art Schools USA, 1955-1957 (Box 23)
    - 55-15: Pioneers of American Abstract Art, 1955 (Box 23)
    - 55-16: In Memoriam, 1955 (Box 23)
    - 55-17: 2,000 Years of Chinese Painting, [1955] (Box 23)
    - 55-18: Fifty Books of the Year, 1955-1957 (Box 23)
    - 55-19: Sport in Art, 1956 (Box 23)
    - 55-19: Sport in Art, 1956 (continued) (Box 24)
    - 55-20: Ninth National Print Annual, 1955-1956 (Box 24)
    - 55-21: Drawing in America, 1955-1956 (Box 24)
    - 55-22: California Designed, 1954-1956 (Box 24)
    - 55-23: Nicholas De Stael, 1955-1956 (Box 24)
    - 55-24: Four Centuries of European Drawings, 1955-1956 (Box 24)
    - 56-1: Whitney Annual 1956 (Box 24)
    - 56-2: Graphic Gala, 1955-1956 (Box 24)
    - 56-3: Adventure in Glass, 1954-1958 (Box 24)
    - 56-3: Adventure in Glass, 1954-1958 (continued) (Box 25)
    - 56-5: Camera Consciousness, 1954-1957 (Box 25)
    - 56-7: A Mid-Century Review: German Watercolors, Drawings and Prints, 1905-1955, 1955-1958 (Box 25)
    - 56-8: Seventeen, 1955-1956 (Box 25)
    - 56-9: Forecast: Museum Director's Choice, 1955-1962 (Box 25)
    - 56-10: Three Renaissance Architects, 1955-1962 (Box 25)
    - 56-11: A Printmaker's View of the 17th Century, 1955-1958 (Box 25)
    - 56-12: New Talent in the USA 1956, 1955-1957 (Box 25)
    - 56-13: Painter's Panorama II, 1955-1957 (Box 25)
    - 56-14: Art Schools USA, , 1961-1962 (Box 25)
    - 56-15: Contemporary Color Lithography, 1955-1958 (Box 25)
    - 56-16: Paintings Prior to 1860, 1953-1957 (Box 25)
    - 56-18: Garden Pieces, 1956-1957 (Box 25)
    - 56-19: The Art Market, 1956-1957 (Box 25)
    - 56-20: UPA: Form in the Animated Cartoon, 1956-1957 (Box 25)
    - 56-21: Prints from Twenty Nations, 1956 (Box 25)
    - 56-21: Prints from Twenty Nations, 1956 (continued) (Box 26)
    - 56-22: Sculpture in Silver from Islands in Time, 1955-1957 (Box 26)
    - 56-23: The Bookbinder's Craft, 1953-1957 (Box 26)
    - 56-24: Art in Science, 1956-1959 (Box 26)
    - 56-25: Tenth National Print Annual, 1955-1957 (Box 26)
    - 56-26: A Decade of Prints, 1956-1958 (Box 26)
    - 56-27: Boston Arts Festival, 1956-1958 (Box 26)
    - 56-28: Cuban Tempos, 1956-1962 (Box 26)
    - 56-29: Young Artists of the Near East, 1956-1959 (Box 26)
    - 57-1: Whitney Annual 1957, 1956-1958 (Box 26)
    - 57-2: Children of the City, 1956-1958 (Box 26)
    - 57-2: Children of the City, 1956-1958 (continued) (Box 27)
    - 57-3: The American Cartoon, 1955-1958 (Box 27)
    - 57-4: The Tastemakers, 1955-1957 (Box 27)
    - 57-5: Theater Designs of Donald Oenslager, 1956-1958 (Box 27)
    - 57-6: Craftsmanship in a Changing World, 1956-1957 (Box 27)
    - 57-9: Executive View, 1956-1957 (Box 27)
    - 57-10: Corcoran Biennial, 1956-1959 (Box 27)
    - 57-11: Fifty Years at the Corcoran, 1955-1958 (Box 27)
    - 57-12: New Talent in the USA 1957, 1956-1957 (Box 27)
    - 57-13: Painters Panorama Ill, 1955-1957 (Box 27)
    - 57-14: Young Americans - Young Scandinavians, 1956-1957 (Box 27)
    - 57-15: Major Works in Minor Scale, 1956-1959 (Box 28)
    - 57-16: Look At America, 1956-1959 (Box 28)
    - 57-17: Posters USA, 1955-1959 (Box 28)
    - 57-18: Illuminations, 1955-1960 (Box 28)
    - 57-19: World Art, 1956-1957 (Box 28)
    - 57-20: International Kites, 1957-1958 (Box 28)
    - 57-21: Frans Masereel: Graphic Work, 1956-1957 (Box 28)
    - 57-22: The Prints of Reginald Marsh, 1956-1959 (Box 28)
    - 57-23: Contemporary Texas Painting, 1956-1959 (Box 28)
    - 57-24: Structural Steel in Today's Architecture, 1956-1960 (Box 28)
    - 57-25: Abstract Photography, 1957-1958 (Box 28)
    - 57-26: Pictures of "My Mother,", 1956-1960 (Box 28)
    - 57-27: AFA Preview: Younger Europeans, 1957-1958 (Box 28)
    - 57-28: A Collector's Choice: Selections by William H. Lane, 1956-1958 (Box 29)
    - 57-29: A Visit to 17th Century Holland, 1957 (Box 29)
    - 57-30: In Memoriam, 1957 (Box 29)
    - 57-31: Art Schools USA 1957 (Box 29)
    - 57-32: Fourteen Painter-Printmakers, 1957 (Box 29)
    - 57-33: Italian Art of the 20th Century, 1957 (Box 29)
    - 57-35: Four Florida Artists: Massin, Pachner, Solomon Zerbe, 1957-1958 (Box 29)
    - 57-36: A University Collects-Michigan, 1957 (Box 29)
    - 57-37: The Life of Christ, 1956-1960 (Box 29)
    - 57-38: Forged in Fire, 1957-1958 (Box 29)
    - 57-39: The Decisive Moment: Photographs by Cartier-Bresson, 1930-1957, 1957-1960 (Box 29)
    - 57-40: The Arts of Norway, 1957-1959 (Box 29)
    - 57-41: Sculpture by Roszak, 1957 (Box 29)
    - 58a/b: The Photographer's Choice: The Best from Life, 1958-1961 (Box 29)
    - 58EE: From the Executive's Easel, 1956-1960 (Box 30)
    - 58-1: The Houses of Today, 1958 (Box 30)
    - 58-3: 11th National Print Exhibition, 1957-1959 (Box 30)
    - 58-4: Kaleidoscope, 1957-1959 (Box 30)
    - 58-5: Whitney Annual 1957-1958 (Box 30)
    - 58-6: Paintings and Prints from the Upper Midwest-Walker Art Center Biennial, 1957-1959 (Box 30)
    - 58-7: West Coast Artists, 1957-1959 (Box 30)
    - 58-9: The Baroque Illusion, 1957-1960 (Box 30)
    - 58-10: The Heroic Encounter, 1957-1960 (Box 30)
    - 58-11: Robert Edmond Jones Designs for the Theater, 1957-1959 (Box 30)
    - 58-11: Robert Edmond Jones Designs for the Theater, 1957-1959 (continued) (Box 31)
    - 58-12: New Talent, 1958 (Box 31)
    - 58-14: The Charm of Youth, 1957-1959 (Box 31)
    - 58-15: Contemporary Color Lithography, 1956-1960 (Box 31)
    - 58-16: God and Man in Art, 1957-1959 (Box 31)
    - 58-16: God and Man in Art, 1957-1959 (continued) (Box 32)
    - 58-17: Japanese Prints, 1957-1958 (Box 32)
    - 58-18: Manzu and Morandi, 1957-1958 (Box 32)
    - 58-19: Who Was Rembrandt?, 1957-1958 (Box 32)
    - 58-20: Faces in American Art, 1957-1959 (Box 32)
    - 58-21: Fourteenth Century Frescos, 1957-1958 (Box 32)
    - 58-22: German Expressionist Works Collected by Richard L. Feigen, 1957 (Box 32)
    - 58-23: Painting in Postwar Italy, 1957-1962 (Box 32)
    - 58-24: Stone Rubbings of Pre-Columbian Monuments, 1957-1959 (Box 32)
    - 58-25: Contemporary Wall Hangings, 1958 (Box 32)
    - 58-26: Collage in America, 1958-1959 (Box 32)
    - 58-27: A Hundred Years Ago, 1957-1959 (Box 32)
    - 58-28: The Postwar Church in Germany, 1958-1962 (Box 33)
    - 58-29: Six from Paris, 1958-1959 (Box 33)
    - 58-30: Sculpture from Prison Bars, 1957-1958 (Box 33)
    - 58-31: Painters Under Twelve, 1958-1959 (Box 33)
    - 58-32: Young Americans 1958, 1957-1958 (Box 33)
    - 58-33: Contemporary Korean Painting, 1958 (Box 33)
    - 58-34: Adventures in Collecting, 1957-1958 (Box 33)
    - 58-35: Today's Religious Art, 1957-1960 (Box 33)
    - 58-36: Forms from Israel, 1958-1960 (Box 33)
    - 58-36: Forms from Israel, 1958-1960 (continued) (Box 34)
    - 58-37: Pre-Columbian Art, 1957-1958 (Box 34)
    - 58-38: Contemporary Danish Design, 1957-1960 (Box 34)
    - 58-39: Art Schools USA 1958, 1958-1960 (Box 34)
    - 58-40: The Figure in Contemporary Drawing, 1958-1959 (Box 34)
    - 58-41: A Sculpture by DeRivera, 1958-1959 (Box 34)
    - 58-42: Crosscurrents, 1955-1959 (Box 34)
    - 58-43: New Landscapes in Art and Science, 1958-1960 (Box 34)
    - 58-44: Portrait of a Building: 100 Church Street, 1958 (Box 34)
    - 58-45: Art in Animation, 1958-1960 (Box 34)
    - 58-45: Art in Animation, 1958-1960 (continued) (Box 35)
    - 59-1: Whitney Annual, 1958-1959 (Box 35)
    - 59-2: Renaissance Bronzes, 1958-1959 (Box 35)
    - 59-3: Canadian Watercolors and Graphics, 1956-1960 (Box 35)
    - 59-4: Native Arts of the Pacific Northwest, 1958-1960 (Box 35)
    - 59-5: Art Exhibition Posters from Paris, 1957-1959 (Box 35)
    - 59-6: The American Line, 1958-1960 (Box 35)
    - 59-7: Ten Modern Masters of American Art, 1958-1965 (Box 35)
    - 59-8: Abstract Art in Ancient Textiles, 1957-1959 (Box 36)
    - 59-10: Corcoran Biennial 1959, 1959-1960 (Box 36)
    - 59-12: New Talent in the USA, 1959, 1958-1960 (Box 36)
    - 59-13: Trends in Contemporary Indian Painting, 1958-1960 (Box 36)
    - 59-14: Art and the Found Object, 1958-1959 (Box 36)
    - 59-15: Form Givers at Mid-Century (Alvar Aalto, Marcel Breuer, R. Buckminster Fuller, Wallace K. Harrison, Philip Johnson, Gyorgy Kepes, LeCorbusier, Mies van der Rohe, Eero Saarinen, SOM, Edward Durrell Stone, Louis Sullivan, Frank Lloyd Wright), 1958-1960 (Box 36)
    - 59-15: Form Givers at Mid-Century, 1958-1960 (continued) (Box 37)
    - 59-16: New Paintings from Yugoslavia, 1958-1962 (Box 37)
    - 59-17: The Private World of Pablo Picasso, 1958-1960 (Box 37)
    - 59-18: Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Folk Art, 1958-1962 (Box 37)
    - 59-18: Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Folk Art, 1958-1962 (continued) (Box 38)
    - 59-19: Fifty Years of Ballet Design, 1959-1960 (Box 38)
    - 59-20: Two French Realists: Daumier and Callot, 1958-1961 (Box 38)
    - 59-21: Mexico Today, 1958-1961 (Box 38)
    - 59-22: Indian Art in the United States, 1958-1962 (Box 38)
    - 59-23: Artists as Collectors, 1957-1960 (Box 38)
    - 59-24: A Rationale for Modern Art, 1958-1960 (Box 38)
    - 59-24: A Rationale for Modern Art, 1958-1960 (continued) (Box 39)
    - 59-25: Street Furniture, 1958-1959 (Box 39)
    - 59-27: Architecture of Puerto Rico, 1958-1961 (Box 39)
    - 59-28: Sculpture: The Work of Costatino Nivola, 1959-1961 (Box 39)
    - 59-29: Creative Engineering: The Work of Nervi, 1959-1961 (Box 39)
    - 59-30: Landscape Design: The Work of Dan Kiley, 1958-1959 (Box 39)
    - 59-31: Trustees' Choice, 1958-1960 (Box 39)
    - 59-32: Bayre: Sculpture and Drawings, 1959 (Box 39)
    - 59-34: Major Works in Minor Scale, 1958-1959 (Box 39)
    - 59-35: Contemporary Italian Drawings and College, 1960-1961 (Box 39)
    - 59-36: German Graphic Art of the 20th Century, 1959 (Box 39)
    - 59-38: Kaethe Kollwitz, 1959 (Box 39)
    - 59-40: Five Centuries of Drawing, 1959-1960 (Box 39)
    - 59-40: Five Centuries of Drawing, 1959-1960 (continued) (Box 40)
    - 59-41 to 59-52: Ford Foundation Retrospectives (Box 40)
      - 59-41: Milton Avery Retrospective, 1959-1962 (Box 40)
      - 59-42: Andrew Dasburg Retrospective, 1959-1961 (Box 40)
      - 59-43: Lee Gatch Retrospective, 1959 (Box 40)
      - 59-43: Lee Gatch Retrospective, 1959 (continued) (Box 41)
      - 59-44: Mauricio Lasansky Retrospective, 1959-1962 (Box 41)
      - 59-45: Carl Morris Retrospective, 1962 (Box 41)
      - 59-46: William Pachner Retrospective, 1959-1962 (Box 41)
      - 59-47: Walter Quirt Retrospective, 1959-1960 (Box 41)
      - 59-47: Walter Quirt Retrospective, 1959-1960 (continued) (Box 42)
      - 59-48: Abraham Rattner Retrospective, 1959-1962 (Box 42)
      - 59-49: Karl Schrag Retrospective, 1959-1962 (Box 42)
      - 59-50: Everet Spruce Retrospective, 1959-1961 (Box 42)
      - 59-51: Jose DeCreeft Retrospective, 1959-1962 (Box 42)
      - 59-52: Hugo Robus Retrospective, 1959-1962 (Box 42)
    - 59-53: Teenage Painting from Israel, 1959-1960 (Box 42)
    - 59-53: Teenage Painting from Israel, 1959-1960 (continued) (Box 43)
    - 59-54: Flannagan: Sculpture and Other Works, 1959 (Box 43)
    - 59-56: Photography in the Fine Arts, 1959-1960 (Box 43)
    - 60-1: Whitney Annual 1959-1960 (Box 43)
    - 60-2: Wood Sculpture and Graphics, 1959-1961 (Box 43)
    - 60-3: Twelfth National Print Exhibition, 1959-1960 (Box 43)
    - 60-4: Private Worlds, 1960 (Box 43)
    - 60-5: Designer Craftsmen USA, 1960, 1959-1960 (Box 43)
    - 60-6: Japanese Art Treasures, 1959-1960 (Box 43)
    - 60-7: Flavor and Fragrance, 1958-1960 (Box 43)
    - 60-8: Marsden Hartley, 1960-1962 (Box 43)
    - 60-8: Marsden Hartley, 1960-1962 (continued) (Box 44)
    - 60-9: Some Younger American Artists, 1959-1960 (Box 44)
    - 60-12: New Talent in the USA, 1960 (Box 44)
    - 60-13: Highlights of American Painting, 1960 (Box 44)
    - 60-14: The Aldrich Collection, 1959-1962 (Box 44)
    - 60-15: International Prints, Documentation, 1960-1962 (Box 44)
    - 60-16: Achievement in the Building Arts, 1959-1960 (Box 44)
    - 60-17: South American Art Today, 1960-1961 (Box 44)
    - 60-18: Exotic Art, 1959-1961 (Box 44)
    - 60-20: The New Generation of Italian Art, 1959-1961 (Box 44)
    - 60-20: The New Generation of Italian Art, 1959-1961 (continued) (Box 45)
    - 60-21: Atget in Paris 1900-1925, 1960-1962 (Box 45)
    - 60-22: Graphics '59, 1959-1960 (Box 45)
    - 60-23: Perception and Visual Expression, 1958-1962 (Box 45)
    - 60-24: Unique Impressions, 1959-1961 (Box 45)
    - 60-25: Paris Vivant, 1960-1961 (Box 45)
    - 60-27: Major Paintings from the Whitney, 1900-1957, 1960 (Box 45)
    - 60-28: The Hudson River School, 1960-1961 (Box 45)
    - 60-29: Abstract Expressionist Drawings, 1961 (Box 45)
    - 60-30: Cameron Booth Retrospective, 1961 (Box 45)